hello and welcome to the video about the
您好，欢迎观看有关本
specific and matin heat laboratory
实验室练习中的比热和晨热实验室
exercise in this laboratory exercise
练习的视频，
you're going to be measuring the
您将测量
specific heat of water and the latent
水的比热和
heat of fusion of ice so in order to
冰的熔化潜热，因此为了
measure the specific heat of water
测量水的比热，
you're going to be submerging a small
您 将一个小型
heating element into a known amount of
加热元件浸入已知量的
water you're then going to be using your
水中，然后您将使用您的
power is equal to energy divided by time
功率等于能量除以时间
relationship so P is it cool - its
关系，因此 P 是否凉爽-它的
energy but the energy is in the form of
能量，但能量是以热量的形式
heat in this case on time relationship
在这种情况下，关于时间
and the relationship between energy Q
关系以及能量 Q
heat energy and the specific heat M C
热能与比热 M C
delta T which is the final temperature
delta T 之间的关系，即最终温度
minus the initial temperature in order
减去初始温度，
to find C the specific heat of water so
以便找到 C 水的比热，这样
you'll know how much energy you've added
你就会知道你有多少能量 已添加，
because you'll be able to measure the
因为您将能够
amount of power going in using P is
使用 P 测量进入的功率量
equal to V I voltage times current we
等于 V I 电压乘以电流，我们
should two quantities that you will be
应该
measuring with your multimeter so this
使用万用表测量两个量，所以这
is how you're going to do the first part
就是您的方式 o 在第二部分
of the experiment in the second part
中进行实验的第一部分，
you're going to be measuring the latent
您将测量
heat of fusion of ice so in this part
冰融化的潜热，因此在这一部分中，
you're going to be submerging ice in
您将把冰浸入
water and measuring the temperature
水中并测量
before and after the ice is melted and
冰融化前后的温度 融化，
then using Q is equal to the mass of ice
然后使用 Q 等于冰的质量
times the latent heat of fusion and
乘以熔化的潜热，
you'll also be able to work out the heat
您还可以
transfer by looking at the change in
通过观察
temperature of the water around the ice
冰周围水的温度
and considering the change in
变化并考虑温度变化来计算热传递
temperature of the ice after it's melted
融化后的冰块，
as well so let's have a look at the
让我们看看
equipment that you'll be using now
您现在将使用
this is the equipment that you'll be
的设备 这是您将
using for this experiment you should set
用于此实验的设备 您应该
your power supply to six volts using the
使用小开关将电源设置为 6 伏
little switch on the side you'll also
一边你
have two multimeters one is going to be
还有两个万用表，一个将
used as an ammeter for the ammeter you
用作电流表的电流表，你
should use the unfused setting as the
应该使用未熔断设置作为
power output set around 2.5 amps and
功率输出设置在 2.5 安培左右，
this will blow the fuse if you use the
如果你使用电压表的保险丝设置，这会烧断保险丝
fuse setting for the voltmeter use the
使用
fuse setting you'll also have a switch
f 使用设置，您还将有一个开关，
because you don't want the current
因为您不希望在不加热水
flowing through your resistor when it's
时电流流过电阻器，
not heating the water you'll have your
您将拥有
logger Pro with a temperature probe to
带有温度探头的 logger Pro 来
measure the temperature of the water and
测量水的温度，并且
you also have two kilometers one of
您还有两个 公里
these Kalorama ters has a resist
这些Kalorama ter中的一个有一个
resistor whether the little coil of wire
电阻电阻器，这里的小线圈
here which you'll use as a heating
用作加热
element and the other has no resistor
元件，另一个没有电阻器，
you'll be using the second one to
您将使用第二个电阻器来
measure the latent heat of fusion of ice
测量冰熔化的潜热
the calorimeter is just a aluminium can
热量计只是一个
surrounded by polystyrene polystyrene is
被聚苯乙烯包围的铝罐 聚苯乙烯
not a good thermal conductor so this is
不是良好的导热体，所以这
going to insulate it and stop the heat
将使其绝缘并阻止热量
escaping out the site so in order to
从现场逸出，所以为了
start this experiment you're going to
开始这个实验，你
need to measure the mass of aluminium so
需要测量铝的质量
in order to do that carefully unscrew
所以为了做到这一点，小心地
the plastic top from the top of the
从铝搅拌器顶部拧下塑料顶部，
aluminium stirrer being very careful to
非常小心地
place it somewhere safe so that you
将它放在安全的地方，这样你
don't lose it
就不会丢失它
and then measure the mass of the
，然后测量
aluminium can plus the stirrer on the
铝 c 的质量 加上
scales which will be at the side of the
将在实验室一侧的天平上的搅拌器
lab record this mass and then use the
记录这个质量，然后使用
tap at the side of the lab to fill your
实验室一侧的水龙头将您的
Kalorama tucán to about two-thirds full
Kalorama tucán 填充到大约三分之二，
you can then measure the mass again
然后您可以在之前再次测量质量
either before or after collecting your
或者在收集你的
temperature measurements and from the
温度测量值以及
difference in the mass now and the mass
现在和之前质量的差异之后，
beforehand I can work out how much water
我可以计算
is in that color ometer so once you've
出那个色度计中有多少水，所以一旦你
done that you're ready to start
完成了，你就可以开始
recording your measurements
记录你的测量结果了
so you're going to need to set up your
需要设置你的
circuit remember that the ammeter goes
电路记住，电流表
in series with the resistor and the
与电阻串联，
voltmeter needs to go in parallel across
电压表需要并联
it you need to measure the voltage in
，你需要测量
the current in order to calculate the
电流中的电压以计算
power so may commit record of what these
功率，所以可能会记录这些
are at the start of the five minutes
在
before as you heat the water and at the
你加热水之前的五分钟开始和
end of the five minutes as well so let's
五分钟结束时，所以让
just quickly wire that up now I need my
我们快速连接它现在我需要我的
power coming out of my power supply into
电源从我的电源进入
my switch then out of my switch into my
我的开关，然后从我的 进入我的
ammeter for which I'm using the unfused
电流表，我正在使用我的电流表中的未熔丝
setting out of my ammeter and into my
设置并进入我的
resistor and then out of my resistor
电阻器，然后从我的电阻器中
back into my power supply in a nice loop
以一个很好的回路重新进入我的电源，
so now the switch and the ammeter in
所以现在开关和电流表
series with the resistor I now plug my
与我现在的电阻器串联
when your circuit parts set up leave the
当您的电路部件设置好时，将我的电压表并联到电阻器上，让
switch open so that we're not currently
开关保持打开状态，这样我们目前就不会
heating the water and set up the logger
加热水并设置记录仪
Pro so the logger Pro remember needs
Pro，因此记录仪 Pro 记住需要
three attachments the power to the USB
三个附件，将电源连接到
at port at the back of the computer and
USB 端口 计算机背面和
to the temperature probe you can switch
可以切换
put the temperature probe through the
的温度探头 将温度探头穿过
hole in the lid of the calorimeter make
热量计盖子上的孔
that set up open the template on your
在您的
computer so go to experiments logger Pro
计算机上打开模板，然后转到实验记录器 Pro
and then select select the specific and
，然后
latent heat experiment when you're ready
在您准备好收集数据时选择选择特定的潜热实验
to collect the data open the sorry close
打开抱歉
the switch press collect and then make
关闭开关 h 按收集键，然后
sure that you're continuously gently
确保你不断地轻轻
stirring the water so that the water
搅拌水，使
inside the calorimeter
热量计内的水
throughout the experiment when you just
在整个实验过程中保持热平衡。
when you finished recording for five
用五
minutes record the current and the
分钟记录实验室中的电流和
voltage in your lab manual switch off
电压，手动
the switch move it to the open position
关闭开关，将其移至打开位置
so that the currents no longer flowing
，使电流不再流
through it and then stop recording on
过它，然后停止在计算机上
your specific amount heat template on
的特定热量模板
the computer now you should have a nice
上记录，现在你应该有一个 漂亮的
straight upwards trend what you're going
直线上升趋势
to need to do is fit a straight line to
您需要做的是拟合一条直线
that so highlight or the data from when
，以便突出显示或加热时的数据，
it was being heated and hit the straight
然后点击
line tool at the top that's going to
顶部的直线工具，这将为
give you the gradient for this line in
您提供这条线的渐变
the theoretical problems you're going to
在理论问题中，你会
come up with a relationship between the
想出
gradient of this line and the specific
这条线的梯度和水的比
heat of water so you may want to have a
热之间的关系，所以你可能想要一个
think about that before you come to the
thi  nk 在你来实验室之前，
lab when you've done it for one sample
当你完成一个
for five minutes
样品五分钟后
empty the water from the colorama tar
，将 colorama 焦油中的水清空
into the sink refill it with cold water
到水槽中，用冷水重新装满它，
ever think about why you'd want to do it
想想你为什么
with cold water instead of just
要用冷水来做 而不是仅仅
continuing to heat the already warm
继续加热已经温热的
water and repeat this at least another
水并至少再重复
two times so that you have three
两次，这样您就可以
measurements of CW from your gradient
从梯度中获得三个 CW 测量值，
and you can calculate an uncertainty in
并且您可以在本实验的第二部分计算
your value for CW
CW 值的不确定性
you're going to be measuring the latent
将要测量
heat of fusion of ice you need to come
冰熔化的潜热 你需要
up with your own method to do this
想出自己的方法来做到这一点
you've got a separate calorimeter
你有一个单独的热量计
that you can use you've got water in the
，你可以使用 你的
tap it provides both warm and cold water
水龙头里有水 它提供温水和冷水
you've got ice in the ice machine a hint
你 制冰机里有冰 这个实验的提示
with this experiment is a good idea to
是一个好主意，在
dry your ice cubes on a piece of paper
将冰块
towel before placing them into the
放入 Kalorama Terr 之前，先用一张纸巾擦干冰块
Kalorama Terr have a think about why
想想为什么
you'd want to dry those ice cubes you
要干燥这些冰块
can then use the temperature probe or
然后可以使用温度 探头或
whatever you think is the best method to
任何您认为是
measure the latent heat of fusion of ice
测量冰熔化潜热的最佳方法
make sure that you take enough
确保您进行了足够的
measurements so that you can also
测量，以便您
now with this equipment when you return
现在可以使用此设备计算结果中的不确定性，当您
up to the hatch it's important that you
返回舱口时，这很重要
return it in the same state you got it
您以与收到时相同的状态退回它，
so you're going to need to make sure
因此您需要
that you've dried everything with paper
确保已用纸巾擦干所有东西
towel please don't return the equipment
请不要退回设备
or wet make sure that the outside of the
或弄湿 确保
polystyrene inside the calorimeter is
热量计内聚苯乙烯的外部
dry okay thanks and I hope that you
干了，谢谢，我希望你
enjoy and learn a lot from this
喜欢这个实验并从中学到很多东西